## Gide Segid

## Backend developer, Database administrator, Full stack developer



Address:Hofstraat 39 Nijmegen

Tele:0031686341402

Email:gidesegid@gmail.com

Birthdate:01-01-1985

As a back-end Developer I create, code, and improve the server, server-side applications, and databases that, when combined with front-end codes, help create a functional, seamless experience for the end-user. I study industry trends, create or improve back-end processes and codes, and work with others to design a better program.

### **Experience**

#### Cubiceys Maarsen --backend web developer 2021-present

As a backend developer, I am working on a huge project in which we use node js, graphql and serverless are intensively used by the project.

#### Toevast Oss --full stack web developer 2020-2021

Designing user interactions on websites, developing servers and databases for website functionality and coding for mobile platforms. Particularly responsible for developing front end and backend website architecture.

Programming languages and Javascript frameworks I have used while working at this company were:

Html5, CSS, Vanilla Javascript, Openlayers, Angularis, React, Nodejs, Mysql, MongoDB

# Renswoude Gis, Heeswijk-Dinther --GIS specialist and web based map developer and full stack engineer 2019- 2020

I build and maintained GIS database postgresql, and used Arc-GIS-Desktop software and qGIS to analyze the spatial and non-spatial information in them. Using the help of javascript framework openlayers, I could make a web based map application. Programming languages and frameworks I have used at this company were: Arc-gis, Qgis, Openlayers, Javascript, Html, Css, Angularjs, Reactjs

#### Freelancer, Amsterdam ---Full stack web developer 2016 - 2018

Writing well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices. Creating website layout/user interfaces by using standard HTML/CSS practices. Integrating data from various back-end services and databases of different clients. Programming languages I have using during my freelancing, Html, Css, Javascript, Angularis, Reactis, React-native, Nodejs, Mysgl, MongoDB.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Eritrea Institute Technology ,Eritrea -- Degree 2007 - 2011

I have studied computer science in Eritrea and I have got a bachelor degree. When I came to the Netherlands then my degree has been evaluated as equal with the computer science degree from the university in the Netherlands.

#### Hackyourfuture, Amsterdam -- course

January 2016-Juli 2016 I took a web development course at Hackyourfuture just for recap. Since I have studied computer science and I had long time work experience in software development, that time was in need for me to take web development just to reinforce my knowledge over web development. Because I love web development much more than software development and it was easy to get a job in the web development as well.

#### SIMPLILEARN, ONLINE -COURSE 2019

I have completed a data science course with python programming language online. The reason that I took this course was just I saw the trend toward the importance of data science and I saw it really muches with my skills that I have already on the databases.

#### **SKILLS**

- 1) Web developer (Backend and/or full stack)
- 2) Database administrator

#### extras/plus

- Mobile app developer
- Data scientist
- GIS specialist
- Software developer
- Network administrator
- Aws, serverless, nginx, docker and other backend server configurations

## **Projects**

- https://www.duurzamedata.nl --gives energy label information of any building in the Netherlands.
  - https://www.tgclean.nl -- is a cleaning service website which I have developed for a private company.
  - Tigrinya word translation-- translation app which translated from Tigrinya to other languages including english and dutch and more others. I created the app in a modern framework react native.
  - www.yourhelplab.com -- Job search web app. This project is developed by me which I
    have done it all the way from front end to backend. I have used node js and mysql in the
    backend and vanilla javascript html and css in the front end.

#### Here is my public github repo @Gide Segid.

Nodejs-typescript---React-typescript: <a href="https://github.com/gidesegid/nodeJs\_react\_typescript.git">https://github.com/gidesegid/nodeJs\_react\_typescript.git</a>

react-Hook: https://github.com/gidesegid/react\_sample\_project.git

Serverless: <a href="https://github.com/gidesegid/Serverless lambda-function.git">https://github.com/gidesegid/Serverless lambda-function.git</a>

#### **AWARDS**

Technology awards festival Eritrea 2012

I have been awarded as innovator of software developer for I have created a new software which calculated the cost of a building. This software helped contractors to estimate the cost of any building project beforehand.

#### Language

English, Dutch, Tigrina

NB:In this CV I have not listed experience that I had in software development and GIS skills because it is outdated and I have shifted to web development. Otherwise my skills and experiences on software development began in 2011 just after my graduation .So not to create complexity in my cv I just preferred to leave them from mentioning in this cv.